Regi Kusumaatmadja

(last update: January 2021)

Amsterdam, 1082 MS, The Netherlands (+31)-6-33-204-172 or r.kusumaatmadja@tinbergen.nl Profiles: LinkedIn and GitHub

SHORT PROFILE

Regi is currently pursuing his graduate study (MPhil/Ph.D. Track) at Tinbergen Institute, The Netherlands. Regi is a former researcher at LPEM FEB UI. He was mainly responsible for supervising data management and assisting (Co)Project Investigators in analysis and writing. He has worked with a broad spectrum of decision-makers from government agencies, private corporate, and non-profit organizations.

Regi has research interests in Industrial Organization, Applied Econometrics, and Innovation. He has also developed interests in Urban-related issues.

EDUCATION

MPhil/PhD Track, Economics

Aug 2019 - now

Tinbergen Institute, Amsterdam & Rotterdam, The Netherlands

MSc, Economics Aug 2017 - July 2018

VU Amsterdam, Amsterdam, The Netherlands

GPA: 8.1/10, Cum Laude

Thesis: Trade and wage-setting power: Evidence from China's accession to WTO

BSc, Physics Aug 2012 - Aug 2016

Universitas Indonesia, Depok, Indonesia

GPA: 3.75/4.00, *Cum Laude*, 1^{st} rank in the department, 2^{nd} rank in the faculty Concentration: Theoretical and Computational Condensed Matter Physics

EXPERIENCE

Research and Teaching Assistants

Sept 2020 - Present

Department of Economics & Department of Spatial Economics - VU Amsterdam

- Research Assistant for Profs. Sabien Dobbelaere and Eric Bartelsman for the project EU HORIZON 2020 MICROPROD at Dept. of Economics (0.2 FTE)
 - Managed data-cleaning of Dutch microdata and other related data (e.g., CIS survey), and wrote codes from seminal paper (e.g., Hsieh and Klenow (2009))
- Teaching Assistant under Profs. Hans Koster and Jos van Ommeren at Dept. of Spatial Economics (*0.1 FTE*)
 - Real Estate and Urban Planning BSc Minor [Prof. Jan Rouwendal]
 - Transport Economics MSc [Profs. Eric Verhoef, Eric Pels, Vincent van den Berg]
 - <u>Real Estate Finance and Investment</u> MSc [Profs. Jan Rouwendal and Foort Hamelink]
 - Real Estate Economics MSc [Profs. Hans Koster and Jan Rouwendal] (scheduled)
 - Invited Guess Lecturer <u>Urban Economic Challenges and Policies</u> MSc
 [Profs. Hans Koster and Jos van Ommeren] (scheduled)

Researcher Aug 2018 - Nov 2019

Institute for Economic and Social Research (LPEM FEB-UI)

Assisting (Co)Investigators in analysis and writing and supervising data management for several research projects

- "Evaluating the impact of Asian Games and WB-IMF on traffic congestion" [funded by Indonesian National Development Planning Agency (Bappenas) and Australian Department of Foreign Affairs and Trade (DFAT)]
- "Estimating the demand for social infrastructures in Asia" [joint with and funded by Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA)]
- "Airlines Industry Liberalization in Indonesia" [funded by a private entity]
- Giving private class on applied econometrics to private entities

Teaching Assistant

Aug 2018 - July 2019

Graduate School of Economics and Public Policy - Universitas Indonesia

- Macroeconomic Theory I + II: RBC, NK, Solow, and RCK
- Applied Econometrics: OLS, IV, Panel Data

AWARDS AND FELLOWSHIPS Awardee, Tinbergen Institute - Full Scholarship (tuition and living cost), 2019 - now

Awardee, VU Amsterdam Fellowship Programme (tuition), 2017

Awardee, Holland Scholarship Programme (living cost), 2017

Best Graduate, Department of Physics, Universitas Indonesia (monetary prizes), 2016 Top 1 (one) Percent, Faculty of Mathematics and Natural Sciences, Universitas Indonesia, 2016

Oral Presenter at International Symposium of Current Progress on Functional Materials (ISCPFM), 2016

Awardee, XL-Axiata Future Leaders Scholarship (XLFL), 2014-2016

Oral Presenter at 9th International Seminar of Magnetic Materials (SMM), 2015 *Awardee*, Karya Salemba Empat Scholarship (tuition and living cost), 2014-2015

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES Chairman of the Faculty Student Council, Jan 2015 - Jan 2016

Head of Religious Division Physics' Student Organization, Jan 2014 - Jan 2015 Attended several prestigious leadership summits: LKMM-UI, PGN, Indofood

PUBLICATIONS

Theoretical exploration of optical response of Fe_3O_4 -reduced graphene oxide nano-

particle system within dynamical mean-field theory (with MA Majidi, AD Fauzi, WY Phan, A Taufik, R Saleh, and A Rusydi)

(With MA Majidi, AD Fauzi, WY Phan, A Taufik, R Saleh, and A Rusydi) IOP Conference Series: Materials Science and Engineering, Volume 188, 2017

WORKING PAPER AND POLICY

REPORT

Does Traffic Management Matter? Evaluating Congestion Effect of Odd-Even Pol-

icy in Jakarta
[Under Revision]

(with M. Halley Yudhistira and M.F. Hidayat)

The Sky in Blues: On the recent development of Indonesian airlines industry (with C. Nuryakin, N. Massie, A. Lumbanraja, S. Hambali, and D. Anindita)

SOFT *Program/Software*: Stata, R, Matlab, LATEX

SKILLS Languages: Bahasa Indonesia (C2/Native), English (C1), Arabic (A2), Dutch (A2)

PERSONAL INTERESTS

Cycling, Learning new language, and Reading

REFERENCES Dr. Sabien Dobbelaere

Associate Professor of Economics
DEPARTMENT OF ECONOMICS, VRIJE UNIVERSITEIT AMSTERDAM
RESEARCH FELLOW, TINBERGEN INSTITUTE AND IZA
E: sabien.dobbelaere@vu.nl

Dr. M. Halley Yudhistira

Assistant Professor of Economics - Head of Graduate School of Public Policy Department of Economics, Universitas Indonesia E: m.halley@ui.ac.id